ODUOR TONNY BLAIR

P.O BOX $342-01000 \cdot +254726720085$,

Email; oduortonny10@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am an accomplished ICT professional with over three years of work experience, demonstrating proficiency in diverse aspects of information technology. My expertise encompasses software development, Intranet administration support, cybersecurity, cloud computing proficiency, ICT project management, Help desk support Specialist, ICT infrastructure expertise, hardware support specialist, System Maintenance with Technical Support, and database administration. I am actively seeking opportunities to apply my skills and knowledge in a dynamic and challenging IT environment.

EXPERIENCE

SEPT 2023 – APRIL 2024 ICT INSTRUCTOR, ANGAZA CENTER NGO.

My responsibilities in partnership with schools;

- Guiding students to come up with projects in areas such as web applications(html,css,javascript,react,nodejs and php(Laravel), and Mobile application projects(flutter with NodeJS).
- Identifying the specific Digital Literacy training needs of individuals and organizations.
- Creating and developing instructional training materials and aids, including handbooks, visual materials, online tutorials, and reference documents.
- Designing, coordinating, and delivering training and development programs, including individual and group instruction, workshops, demonstrations, and conferences.
- Continuously assessing and evaluating the quality and effectiveness of training programs, adjusting objectives, methods, and course content as needed.
- Creating user-friendly training materials such as manuals, online help resources, and operating instructions.
- Conducting research to stay up-to-date with the latest technology trends, software updates, and IT advancements
- Technical Support and Troubleshooting.
- Computer and ICT Equipment Maintenance Expertise.

JUNE 2022 – JUNE 2023

ICT ASSISTANT, MACHEO CHILDRENS NGO

My responsibilities;

- Software Development/Maintenance: Developed a fleet management system using OOP pHp programming language.
- User Account Management and Access Control
- Serve as a Database Administrator
- Intranet Administration and support.
- MS Office365/Microsoft 365 Installation
- Computer and ICT Equipment Maintenance Expertise.
- User Account Management and Access Control
- Technical Support and Troubleshooting
- Data Visualization and Reporting Expertise with Power BI, Advanced Excel, and Anaconda Python:
- Cybersecurity and Information Protection
- ICT Project Management

SEPT 2021 – MARCH 2022

INTERNSHIP AS ICT ASSISTANT, MACHEO CHILDRENS NGO.

My responsibilities were;

- Network Administration
- Technical Support and Troubleshooting
- Junior Software Development(pHp).

JAN 2018 – APRIL 2018 VOLUNTEER AS COMPUTER TRAINER, AHERO MULTIPURPOSE DEVELOPMENT

TRAINING INSTITUTE.

- G-Suit applications: Google workspace services for communication, document creation, scheduling in cloud-based plus domain management and email systems.
- Microsoft office suite.

EDUCATION

MAY 2018 - JULY 2022.

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION AND TECHNOLOGY,

MOUNT KENYA UNIVERSITY

2014-2017

KENYA CERTIFICATE OF SECONDARY EDUCATION,

RAMBA HIGH SCHOOL

SKILLS

- Full Stack Developer: Expertise in programming languages ie, php, dart and JavaScript with familiarity with framework ie ReactJS, ExpressJS, NodeJs for Restful APIs (MERN Stack), Laravel Php and flutter for UI mobile applications.
- Proficient in applying Agile methodologies and ITIL frameworks to optimize project workflows and service operations.
- Database Administration: proficient in utilizing relational database management software packages such as Microsoft SQL Server and MySQL and NoSql databases like MongoDB and firebase.
- CompTIA Certified Network+ Associate with two years of experience in Intranet administration, Efficient at deploying and managing LAN/WAN networking infrastructure and performing troubleshooting activities.
- Computer Hardware and Software Maintenance: Proficient in hardware troubleshooting, deployment, configuration, software installation, and system maintenance for Windows and Linux platforms.
- Experienced in providing specialized support for software applications and offering Helpdesk Administration assistance. Possessing expertise in Web Technologies and System Analysis.
- Data Analysis: Skilled in data analysis using tools such as MS Excel, Anaconda(Python) for data sorting, Power BI for data visualization, MS SQL Server for crafting intricate SQL queries, developing stored procedures, and executing data migration tasks, and MSSQL for creating and managing databases and designing diverse database components.
- Version Control: Proficient in using version control systems such as Git, SVN (Subversion), and Mercurial. Experienced in managing repositories, branching, merging, and resolving conflicts. Familiar with collaborative workflows and code review processes.
- Proficiency in containerization platforms such as Docker and Kubernetes.
- Leverage cloud-based platforms like AWS (Amazon Web Services) and JamStack platforms (Vercel, render and Netlify).

FUNCTIONAL SKILLS

- Goal Oriented.
- Detail-oriented with a high level of accuracy in documenting technical procedures and solutions.
- Ability to work effectively both independently and as part of a collaborative team.
- Enthusiasm for learning and a proactive attitude towards professional development in the field of technical support
- Hardworking, self-driven and ready to learn.
- Quick learner who can withstand stress and get along with Colleagues well.
- Creative, decisive, result-oriented person and team player.
- Able to work under tight and short strict deadlines.
- High personal integrity and ability to tolerate all.
- Ambitious, innovative, and analytical with good interpersonal relations.
- Able to work under minimal and no supervision,
- Good listener.
- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills.

PROFFESIONAL PROFILES.

GitHub: My GitHub profile is a platform where I actively contribute to open-source projects, collaborate with other developers, and showcase my coding skills and projects. It serves as a portfolio of my programming projects and allows potential employers or collaborators to assess my coding proficiency.

- LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tonny-blair-893a0520b/
- GitHub Profile: https://github.com/blair-developer
- Portfolio profile: https://tonnyblair-portfolio.netlify.app/

CERTIFICATION AND TRAINING.

- CompTIA Network+ certification (August 2023).
- Google Associate Android Developer (AAD) by Google Developer Student Club. (September December 2019).
- Help Desk Handbook for End Users: Mobile, Networking, Security and Troubleshooting Certificate by Microsoft and LinkedIn.(April 2024).
- System Administration Certification by Microsoft and LinkedIn (August 2023).
- Data Protection Policy Training by Macheo Children's NGO.(April-June 2022).
- ITIL 4 Fundamentals Essentials of IT Service Management by Allison.(January-2024).

REFEREES

Mr. Ibrahim Hassan, Coordinator,FHN(Programs), Monitoring and Evaluation. Macheo childrens NGO, ibrahimhassankina@gmail.com,

Cell: 0720581278.

Mrs. Harriet Tsinale,
Lecturer, Computing and Informatics,
Tharaka University,
tsinale@yahoo.com,

Mr.Afubwa Musumi Director Career and Alumni services, Mount Kenya University

Cell: 0720178684

Cell: 0725218728